A Guide to the Claude Moore Health Sciences Library Glass Plate Negative Collection, circa 1920-1935
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
The Claude Moore Health Sciences Library Glass Plate Negative Collection, circa 1920-1935
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
MS-56
1 box with the dimensions of 7.5 inches x 5.5 inches x 10.5 inches
University of Virginia
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the University of Virginia Medical Center Marketing Department to the University of Virginia Claude Moore Health Sciences Library circa 2000-2010.
Scope and Content
This collection consists of 29 glass plate negatives illustrating various architectural aspects of the University of Virginia Medical Center and School of Medicine circa 1920-1935, including major hospital renovations and additions.
Arrangement
Materials are arranged according to their original order at the time of their accession to the University of Virginia Claude Moore Health Sciences Library.
Contents List
- Anatomical Theatre, 1930 (Box-folder 1:1)
- Anatomical Theatre, 1929 (Box-folder 1:2)
- Anatomical Theatre, circa 1935 (Box-folder 1:3)
- Medical students in anatomical laboratory, circa 1920-1935 (Box-folder 1:4)
- Medical school histology laboratory, circa 1920-1935 (Box-folder 1:5)
- Medical School Building photography room, circa 1920-1935 (Box-folder 1:6)
- A view of the rear of the University of Virginia Hospital, circa 1927 (Box-folder 1:7)
- The Barringer Wing of the University of Virginia Hospital under construction, 1935 October 2 (Box-folder 1:8)
- The Barringer Wing of the University of Virginia Hospital under construction, 1935 October 9 (Box-folder 1:9)
- The Barringer Wing of the University of Virginia Hospital under construction, 1935 August 7 (Box-folder 1:10)
- Entrance to the University of Virginia Hospital, circa 1930 (Box-folder 1:11)
- A view of the south side of the University of Virginia Hospital, circa 1920 (Box-folder 1:12)
- The Steele Wing of the University of Virginia Hospital, circa 1927 (Box-folder 1:13)
- The Steele Wing and North Pavilion of the University of Virginia Hospital, circa 1925 (Box-folder 1:14)
- University of Virginia Hospital service building, circa 1925 (Box-folder 1:15)
- Teaching laboratory in the University of Virginia Hospital, circa 1925 (Box-folder 1:16)
- The Steele Wing and an annex building of the University of Virginia Hospital, circa 1925 (Box-folder 1:17)
- Annex building attached to the Steele Wing of the University of Virginia Hospital, circa 1925 (Box-folder 1:18)
- Medical School Building at the University of Virginia, circa 1929 (Box-folder 1:19)
- Medical School Building at the University of Virginia, circa 1929 (Box-folder 1:20)
- Architectural sketch of the Medical School Building at the University of Virginia, circa 1927 (Box-folder 1:21)
- University of Virginia Medical Library reading room, circa 1929 (Box-folder 1:22)
- Pavilion VIII at the University of Virginia, circa 1930 (Box-folder 1:23)
- Medical School Building at the University of Virginia, circa 1929 (Box-folder 1:24)
- Dr. Harvey E. Jordan (broken negative), 1929 September 24 (Box-folder 1:25)
- Nurses and patients in a ward of either the North Pavilion or South Pavilion of the University of Virginia Hospital, circa 1920 (Box-folder 1:26)
- University of Virginia Rotunda and Lawn (broken negative), circa 1920-1935 (Box-folder 1:27)
- University of Virginia Rotunda, circa 1920-1935 (Box-folder 1:28)
- Nurses and patients in Ward "E" of the University of Virginia Hospital, circa 1920 (Box-folder 1:29)